WEI SHI

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

I'm a self-taught developer with an engineering background and mindset. I believe in life-long learning, so I'm fully prepared to, (and expect to) adapt to the job at hand. I have over two years of work experience wearing many hats in a small high-tech company. Whatever the role, I strive to do my best.

SKILLS

Languages

Javascript Python C# (Unity) MATLab

Front-End

React Redux HTML5 CSS Sass

Back-End

Node.js Express.js Socket.io REST APIs

Databases

MySQL

MongoDB Mongoose

Other

Git Heroku Adobe Illustrator Blender Adobe After Effects

Current Location
Wichita, KS
Relocating to Dallas, TX
In Winter 2019

Please contact me at

hello@shixwei.com

View my portfolio with demos at shixwei.com

EDUCATION

B.S. in Bioengineering Rice University

Class of 2015 Houston, TX

May 2016 - Feb 2019

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer and Operations

UAVradars LLC, Lawrence, KS

Manipulated, analyzed, and visualized data using MATLab for the calibration and operation of a collision avoidance radar prototype for unmanned aerial vehicles funded by NASA's SBIR Phase II (Small Business Innovation Research).

Designed and implemented software that monitors live radar data and GPS/INS during manned aircraft flight tests.

Managed company website with WordPress, managed company taxes and payroll, created 3D model of radar, & animated introduction video.

Manufacturing Intern

Type-Royale

Boston Scientific, Heredia, Costa Rica

Jun 2015 - Aug 2015

Jul 2019 - Sep 2019

Analyzed and solved problems in manufacturing steps by collecting data and communicating with workers and engineers on the Blazer Dx-20 product line.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

For more details, code, and demos please visit shixwei.com

Multiplayer typing battle-royale web app game made with an Express backend and a React frontend. Real-time interaction with Socket.io. Up to 7

Emaily May 2019 - Jul 2019

players type words to send them at opponents to try to knock them out.

Web app for sending simple yes/no surveys via email en masse at the cost of credits. Uses the MERN stack, Google oAuth, payments with Stripe API, and emailing with SendGrid API.

Backtrack Mar 2019 - Sep 2019

Productivity app that logs computer activity and gives various visualization options. Made as two separate apps, with a Python app for collecting data and Electron app for visualizing data.

Discord Bots Nov 2018 - Jul 2019

I've created two discord bots, Count Bot (Python) and Triple Triad Bot (JS). Count Bot was created for a server that wanted to count together. And Triple Triad Bot let you play the classic card game from FF8 in discord!

Unity Game Engine Projects

May 2016 - Feb 2019

As a hobby I enjoy building game projects with Unity, which uses C# as its scripting language. I also attended the 2019 ICT Game Jam and look forward to attending more in the future.